We will practice the Lion's Dance again,
as far as we have learned it.
I will give you a brief
description of the third stage, the
second stage of the formless space.
We'll do C3.
We'll go through everything we've done today, everything
we've already done.
So, I'll describe it first, and then
we'll do it together. So, the whole thing is called
the Lion's Dance.
We start in the realm of desire,
tasting a
cappuccino, listening to the air conditioning. Then
we go through the stages of the form realm,
concentrating on the heart, and
that still has a
physical component.
Then we go into the four meditations of the
formless realm. The first one
we did yesterday is called
Infinite Space.
So, the body is Marco-focused. The
body is whether you have any awareness of its
form anymore,
and then the mind expands.
You can go as far as if
you put a stone in the cee, and the waves
spread out. Speaking of which,
going from the realm of desire to the realm of fan, you compare
something.
There you have the desire, "I don't want anymore."  I
hear the air conditioning. I want to
go to a quieter place. That's the basic idea
between these realms.
And when you reach the end of the formful realm,
then you are deep in
my heart, and your mind feels—
how should I say it?
—since the feeling of happiness is no longer there.
It's like a flat line.
So again, the feeling of the body is
like when someone has given you an
anesthetic injection, and my
body is taking care of it. And then
you compare this physical heart to
no physical presence.
What is it? It's again a comparison
of the place you are in with
where you want to go. And because you are
making this comparison, you are away from going
there
because even this numb body is too grossly
material. So you want to go to a
subtle place.
And the difference between the first
and second stage of the formless realm
is again a comparison.
For me, the feeling in the
first stage of the formless realm is a
horizontal one. The mind spreads out
like waves on a lake, and it hears
Never go on the waves, always on
and on, and in the second stage of the
formless realm, which we're
discussing here this morning,
when you go from the first stage to the
second stage, it's again a
desire;
you want to go to an even finer level,
and that's why you're now letting go of even
this image of the expansion of the waves.
You want to, you are only conscious. Have you
understood that?
Before, you left the air conditioner behind
because it was too big, and you
wanted something finer, like your heart. It
gets finer and finer. Now
you're letting go of the image of infinite space
because infinite consciousness is even cooler.
[Music]
And normally it takes an hour
to make this transition.
We'll pretend,
so we'll pretend that we're now
going from infinite space to infinite consciousness, but of course, we're still half
in the air conditioner. In the air conditioner realm,
these stages are a goal. No, don't get distracted. Do
n't spend all your time admiring the car at the
airport when you
could be driving home in Susanne's car. So
why practice it then? It's
like...  If you're the one who meets all the standards in the
competition, by the way, she won it in
Colorado, so
you train, you train in
many different places, you run up
and down big mountains when the
competition takes place in a small town,
so for training purposes, if you
maybe run up and down the mountains here,
even if you
run the competition in the flatlands, there's another, a
second goal,
why he practices it, he says seed, seed is
okay, what's a negative purpose?
You don't confuse it with teaching,
you know what I mean?
You don't just randomly go into it, it's not enough to just randomly reach
one of these levels at some point
and then believe that's the apprenticeship,
or you go to a lecture one day
and the teacher describes the
third level and says that's the
majority, then
you can say, yeah, I
know what that's like and I was there and that
's not empty, it's just a
fancy car,
and I think if he practices these new ones
better, the ten, and if you
then go into  If you go to a media
meditation course, then what they
tell you about one of
these 10 seems to correlate with one of these
ten stages. The body
begins its summary with the
following words:
What does it mean that
these mental states of meditation
are negative states?
They are still number one: ignorance.
So if you practice them,
and if you go to a migration course,
and they go to a strange
meditation course, and they
tell you strange things, then you can, of course,
immediately assign in your mind
which stage they refer to.
And at least then it's the case that you're
not attracted to one of these stages.
So we meditate
now, and we often go into
the second stage of the formless realm. Make
sure your phone
is turned off,
relax your forehead,
relax your eyelids, a
small smile
in your stomach, pull in your fingers slightly,
and then we put our mind into
the state of desire. It
's very easy because we're
simply concentrating on the air conditioning.
And now compare this sound to
the sound of a heartbeat,
and then go into your heartbeat,
be the heartbeat
and feel how pleasant it is.
Compare it here to the stillness in
Alaba, compared to the city of Guadalajara.
In the second stage of the Formula Empire,
you no longer have any awareness of the
air conditioning, and how it is in the heartbeat.
And we are inside the
heart, inside the heartbeat. The
body feels light and strong,
and it is a wonderful feeling
to be so still.
Here we will stay for the next few
minutes,
and now you think to yourself, "I want to go further."
This pleasant mental feeling of the
second stage in the anteroom is also
a distraction.
It is nice to be still,
it is pleasant to be still, but I
want to go further.
This pleasant feeling is also
a distraction.
I want to go further.
We will now try to take this
pleasant feeling beyond the Schmidt
silence,
and you compare it to a
state where that is no longer there. It is as
if your mind is covered in dust, and we
Go to this place.
You no longer think about how
beautiful it is to be calm and still.
The body still feels very
good,
strong and healthy.
And now we leave all the feelings of the
body behind, let them go. The
mind has already gone further
than a pleasant feeling,
and now we also leave any
bodily sensation behind. It is as if
the body were numb. In area
number 4, begin further.
Leave the body completely behind, not
you. It is only the stillness of the mind.
You don't even have a
feeling about it anymore. It is simply still, no
feeling about it, simply still.
Now we go further to the formless
realm. I do not want to be limited
by a body.
I will lead my mind away from a
single place, and my
meditation will encompass the entire space, infinite space.
Extend
the meditation into infinity, infinite in
terms of space.
And now say to yourself, I do not want to be
limited by infinite space anymore.
My mind itself is infinitely
boundless,
and I do not want to be limited by this
infinite space anymore.
I can
transcend the space of  Moving through infinite space,
I can simply be my mind,
infinite mind, boundless mind,
without reference to space. And I choose to
go to this even quieter place,
and we are now going directly to the third
stage of the formless realm.
Thinking about your infinite mind, even
without reference to infinite
space, is still a distraction.
I can go even further;
I can also let go of thinking about my
mind, leave it behind.
I came to the awareness of my own mind,
that I think, letting go of
nothing. There we go now, even
quieter,
and now we go to the last and
final stage of the formless realm.
On the second stage, thinking
about my infinite mind is a distraction,
but here on the third stage, a
distraction doesn't know how to think about my mind.
I will go to an even faster place,
to the fourth stage of the formless realm.
I no longer think about my mind,
and no longer try not to
think about my mind. Don't leave that
behind; go even deeper where
nothing is possible anymore, the
quietest place. There we remain.  A few
minutes
and then come back to the breath, three
long exhales,
then it can slowly open your eyes
again. Are
you all right? Is anyone hurt?
What happened? The tree there fell
over. So simple. So
who can? Who can tell me what formless
3 was? Tell me what number two is.
Let go of the endless space and went to the
infinite mind and don't compare it to space
anymore. Don't compare it
to space anymore. And because he was doing so well,
I simply went on to the third
step, to the third stage.
What is that? Was that the object we
deny?
That is the thing that is not present in the majority.
We say it is the thing that is not there in the pen.
What is it?
It is that a piece projected from its side. There is no such thing.
What is
in the kitchen? There is no
married couple who is there because you didn't
yell at your children.
That is that. Gagfah never existed,
could not exist, and will never
exist. Someone who participated in SCM semester
number 2, even the
professor,
can we?  We've discussed the difference between Dacia,
logic, and the character of the path.
It's a short answer because if it's
long, then it's wrong. No, no,
that's not it.
We always have two types of captchas. One
is something that wants to end,
strongly meaning end.
So it's a whole that never existed. That
's a founder. From its side,
the link number one, the misunderstanding
of the founder, also works. That's a disaster. It's
something you want to end
that exists. If you pursue the idea
of ​​the founder further,
it's quite clear that we
want to deny it when thinking.
The husband who just
yelled at me for no reason never existed.
But the idea that he exists from within himself, that
he comes from his
side, that's also what we call an
entrance.
But this whole thing exists, can exist,
and we have to stop it. And
why are we talking about this?
Because in the study of meditation,
when you go from the realm of desire to
the four stages of the realm,
and then from the four of the realm of form
to the next four,
formless.  In this area, there are things at
every step.
You go deeper and deeper into the object,
but in the sense of studying the meditative
mind,
you always say, "That's not enough,
I want it even quieter."
Every time you go to the next stage, something like that happens,
and you say, "It's
not quiet enough, I want it even
quieter." What was the
first
thing that wasn't quiet or still enough? The
air conditioning was audible. What was the
second thing? The heartbeat was too loud from
outside, so we went inside the
heartbeat, and it was quiet. So
beautiful to be so quiet. And then I gave
a hint for next year.
Then you said, "That's beautiful, it's beautiful,
but it's so loud. I want it even quieter.
I don't want my mind to
say, 'Oh, that's beautiful, that it's quiet.' You
say, 'Be quiet,'
that you told me the silence is
beautiful, it's too loud for me."
And then the pleasant feeling of
meditation happened. It's something you let go of so
you can go deeper.
And what came next? What's the next thing that was
very much let go of?  We have
left behind what we had;
we now had a neutral state of mind,
neutral feelings.
I'll give you another hint, but it still felt
totally cool. The
body still felt totally cool,
and also letting go of
how cool it felt, this
physical aspect, balanced in a way similar to ballet.
So, when you feel
symmetrical, aligned, just there, at
the moment you go to the third
stage of the discipline,
your mind said, "It should be, stop telling
me how cool it is,"
but you still have this
aligned feeling of the body, and the
prana flows well. And you also learn to leave that
behind; you let it go, and then
the body feels magical. It's
similar to
when the dentist injects you with cocaine
and you can't feel anything anymore.
So imagine the whole body
is numbed with cocaine.
That's the fourth stage of the Form
Realm. The feelings are already taken care of.
What is that? What is that? Say yes, when you go
from the last stage in the Form Realm to...  The
first stage of the formless realm—
the name should already give you a clue—is where you go.
Why should I focus on myself, on one
point?
I will now concentrate on all points in
space.
Let me extend this meditation
to all points in space, in the universe. What
is the next character?
Why should I compare myself to
infinite space? My mind is
much, much bigger.
I am now also leaving space behind me.
In the second
formless stage, I simply go into
my infinite mind.
And how do we go now? How do we go into
the third? If you can name all four for me,
we'll pause.
Why should I even
think about anything then? Why should I even cling to my
infinite mind? Should I even cling to
my infinite mind?
Even this effort is a
distraction.
I will go to the point where I calmly
cling to nothing anymore. It means that
nothing, nothing, nada, simply
not secure, not attached to anything.
And there was a famous debate in prayer
1250 years ago, and a teacher
said that
the third stage of the
formless realm is...  The direct
experience of the teacher Haid, and if you
can stay there, the richest, and he
was, and that's a false idea, and
I believe, and I believe that at
best, almost all
meditation teachers aim for this: think of
nothing.
It is, it is really very, very
difficult to reach this point. This is the
end goal of meditation, and
now trying to check that, I am so
tired of thinking about it and
deciding to
hold on to something and not hold on to anything.
I will go to a place beyond this
choice. In Tibetan,
this level is called [missing word], it is called [missing word] through
methodological shortcomings. Shower, shower, so not holding on to anything, not holding on to
anything.
My mission is that I wouldn't even have to make
the effort to think of absolutely nothing. I will
also
go beyond that, and everything that arises, I don't care
if the mind wants to hold on to something. I
am not there. The mind decides not to hold on.
I am also not there, real nothing. That is, the
fourth stage of the
formless realm. But if you now do the
dance of the lion, and now
it slowly feels more like dancing, then
you go to a second [missing word], and to
find that out, you would have to go to  Coming back from the break,
we'll see each other in ten or fifteen minutes.
What happens after you decide
not to decide anymore? Speaking of which,
someone asked me,
these are the new stages of meditation
by Kamala Schiller. The seeing stage
is when you're already standing before the project.
These are completely different stages.
These are good Buddhist meditations: overcoming
drowsiness, overcoming attachment,
and developing your tools
until your mind becomes very strong. At
the highest stage,
you see how the monk flies to heaven,
and then they have reached schemas, and
then they combine it with Witts Iana,
which is then the direct experience of
the apprenticeship. Samatha, or deep
meditation, is the starting point from which you
can drive the apprenticeship more directly.
And now I'll tell you something very
interesting: the person who
had the perfect meditation and
reached it more charmingly, and
can thus fly to heaven, they say traditionally
that this happens between the air conditioning
and your heartbeat, so in the first
part of the first stage of the form area,
and that is something completely different. So
that is really the first part
of the first  To reach the first stage of the formless
realm,
DPA China calls the apprenticeship directly, to
experience it
when you have reached Chateau, so
symbolized by the flying one,
and then there is a teacher from Burma
who uses the word like papaya, he
uses the Kali variant, where it means
like pasha, the teacher's name is Co Inc.,
and I studied with him and I did
a long retreat with him
42 years ago,
and that is something else again, they
mainly observe the breath and
they try to
calm the mind, and in the course I did with
him he also
talked a little about suffering,
where would we classify it? I think
somewhere in the form realms
we would classify this meditation from Boeing, as far as
I know, C doesn't teach the
apprenticeship,
so the last classes weren't about
this image,
if you want to study that then come
to this level 3, we'll hide that
again now so that we are not denied,
we go back to the dance of the lion, why, why do
we go through these new
stages of the mind  We
add them to the realm of desire; we do it to
sharpen our minds,
and it's also good for
recognizing what teaches is not
stillness, and it's also good karma. Why mainly
because you can't
commit bad karma as long as
you think about infinite space? Do
these eight bring you a
good result? Well,
you can be reborn in a
higher realm, as a human, and in the
two higher realms,
but you can't leave suffering;
you're still in the Council of Life.
A bodyguard used these eight and
then went to a new level. So, we
have the state of mind in the realm of
desire, then you have the four
states of mind in the form realm,
then you have these states of mind
in the formless realm, and then a word: a
bodyguard was on the first level, but there's
also a debate about that, and they
then go through these new ones,
and then they do something at the end
after they've screwed themselves further and further into it:
Group
Nordic. That's where they go. Group North—
the word means with meditation.  Regarding
termination,
depending on your motivation, you can find
two different types of
meditation in number 92.
If you have a lower motivation,
so not Woody Satisfied,
then when you reach the ninth group,
the meditation of termination begins.
All your feelings, perceptions, and
thought processes cease for a
certain period of time, and they
mistake this for an important goal.
Why does it happen? You are still. You were
kind, and these seeds cause you to
leave this wonderful, peaceful place.  Do you stop your feelings and
your thoughts? So, if you're
not Buddhist, then you stay there, and
what happens after that? These seeds are
exhausted, and then you come
back because you can't stay there
because the seeds eventually run out,
and then you usually pass into a
lower rebirth.
This kind of meditation isn't our
goal; we don't want a meditation where
you think about nothing.
And now, let's define the ending
meditation of a boat.
And before Stanley, I got this from a
lama in the Jackson series. Jackie Jackson
says there are two key figures.
One is the first Jackson lama, but that
's not him here.
This is the most famous manual
writer of Sera. He was born in 1469
and died in 1446, and his
students wrote the manuals for the
monastery where I was. And now,
here's his definition.
If we look for it in the text, we wo
n't find it. Then we
simply continue. There you have it,
exactly. That's the right place.
Why is it called the
ending meditation for a  Let's
take, for example, the meditation
on the apprenticeship of a bodyguard who is at
the sixth stage. There's
a reason
we call it the Completion Meditation.
You know the conclusion: what they
call completion here is empty Hyde,
and they meditate on these majorities,
and that's why we call it the Completion
Meditation.
What has ceased?
The pen,
existing from within itself, has understood.
In the dance of the lion, in this meditation,
you grasp your mind, power the
four stages of the formless realm. You
are like a lion; you collect and
show your power. You say, "I can
do this and that and the other thing." And here,
I can do all these new stages of
meditation. So, the first nine are
really just happening.
I can do this. I can do that with the
heartbeat.
I can also do infinite space. I can do
nothing.
I can do nothing and nothing at all.
But after all these mental
muscle training exercises, I use the
instrument for something important.
I think about the pen and where
the pen comes from.
This speaks of five goals: first,
financial.  Independence.
I don't want to be rich, but I do
n't want to have to think about money.
I don't want to waste my time
thinking about money.
I just want the money to appear in my
backpack so it's there
when I want to buy something.
But I don't want to waste my life thinking
about money, worrying about it.
That's
financial freedom number two. We
also want a good relationship.
It just feels very lonely. It's enough,
but you don't
have a family, friends, or a partner.
And then I also want to be healthy.
I want the energy of a
teenager. Do I have it? There are many
rich people who have
worn themselves out to become so rich.
What was that car again?
No, another car, a
Maserati. Many men in their hormonal
phase from 15 to 95 or 96 think, "
I want a Maserati, and then
all the women would like me." And they work, work, work.
We have
heart problems, and in the end, they earn
enough money to buy the Maserati.
And then they go to the
Maserati, and none of the women want to go with
it.  Getting into a Maserati, we often
waste our strength, our
energy, trying to get money, and a
person with a lot of money but lacking
energy is a very sad
situation. Therefore, one of
the goals is also physical energy. These are
things external, this is what
we want internally: a
peaceful mind,
yes, as if we were
meditating all the time.
Someone says something annoying to us, and you just
say, okay, there's really
bad traffic, okay,
nothing gets upset anymore.
These four things you want for yourself,
and when you're surrounded by many people who do
n't have these four things,
then it's very lonely.
It's like being alone in a big
restaurant to eat alone. There are,
and I often go to,
a restaurant in the wealthy part of
Phoenix, and there you can
see these divorced people
who don't want to cook. They spend
100 dollars for a dinner, an evening meal.
The children go there every evening.
Super lonely, and you can feel it,
enjoying all these things alone, and
other people don't have them.  Do
n't do things,
it's just not fun. That's why
the fifth goal is to share it with other
people.
What's the best way to achieve
the first four for yourself? Then people will ask, "How did
you achieve that? How did you
do that?" Then you won't have to
put up posters for your lectures.
People will come because you
have what they want.
Why am I talking about all this? Because the
reason to see this tenth stage
of meditation, the reason to go there,
the reason to experience the teacher directly, is
the way
to achieve these five goals.
So if someone teaches you a spiritual
path, and safely and in a spiritual
way, especially if
someone says, "I'll teach you the teachings," and
then teach you to give up
thinking, so they teach
you in the third stage of the
formless realm, will that bring you the
achievement of the five goals?
No, the opposite. Speaking of which,
the strange result is that if
you go through this eight as a spiritual practice,
I'll show you on my
phone.
I have it.  I just had that, it's the
terrifying moment
in a modern person's life.
It's reality, is it here?
Why did I show this? The strange
result of practicing these eight
steps is that you
become forgetful. You lose your
car keys, you ca
n't find your phone, you walk across
the room and stop because you forgot
where you were going. Sean
Brady and I call that an age
moment. So, if you're forgetful,
it doesn't necessarily mean you
meditate a lot,
but if you only do these space-taut
meditations, then the
strange result will be that you
lose things, you become forgetful. That's why
it doesn't help you achieve these five
goals. There
's no connection to these five
counting, it's simply a waste of time.
So, if a bodyguard was dancing the Lion's Dance,
those first eight or nine steps,
if you count the air conditioning,
are really just mental
warm-up exercises, and it's just
showing off a bit like jet pilots. We
have a friend, Sean.  Foley,
he was one of the pilots in the movie Top Gun
who do all these things: loops, spins, soaring high.
You're just training your mind
when you finish all these scratching meditations.
South sugar, everyone, I, I, I felt that
you're really attracted to it
because everyone told me what
a wonderful class and
really these minds are responsible for, like
sugar, they're addictive. They're
very quiet, they're very
pleasant, but they're not the goal.
Sean Foley is really a totally nice
man. He got his doctorate from Congress
because he
did all these loops, but the
real reason for his plane is to kill
people.
He told me that during the
war,
I once asked him, "Have you ever killed
anyone?" Well,
bachelor, they sent me. There were
fishing boats that were sinking mines in the sea to blow up
the American
place,
and then he got the order: "
Fly away, and if you
see these fishing boats, sink them." And they do
n't really know which ones are sinking the mines.
And which ones not,
and then he said, "Yes, of course,"
and it flew off, and he
saw a fisherman in red and
flew over it to scout it out, and
they called him from the boat,
and then he turned around and got ready,
and then he received a radio message ending the war,
please cease
all activity,
and this is John's chamber, very, very sweet.
So our goal is not to stop,
we learn all these meditation tricks,
and then we have to jump in the water.
This happened to the pen that
exists on its own, the husband who confronts you, it
's not your fault,
and we have to blow them up.
And these eight new exercises that help
in your mission, the vehicle gets
faster, isn't it cool? So tomorrow
we do one last meditation,
we go through all 8, we go to
number 9, and then we go back again.
You blew up the enemy,
and then on the flight home
you collect more. There's still a little bit of a way,
and that's not the end of the lion's
dance. If you then also do the
follow-up...  There's
another very traditional
exercise to do when the dance of life
is over, and we'll talk about that
tomorrow.
The dance isn't just about going down the eight, then
the ninth, and then coming back again.
That's the
main thing, but there's something extra as well.